(
"ai_sub_version": "3.0.3",
"generated_at": "2026-07-06T02:06:29.536430",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 16,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
Yeah! One, two, check, check, check, check, check.
Check, check. B-Show, Crown B-Show.
Uh, huh.
Yeah, uh-huh, come on, come on, yo, uh...
脳天気野郎 脳天気野郎
Carefree guys, carefree guys!
脳天気野郎ですよ
We're carefree guys!
Zeebra, yeah. How's show?
Zeebra, yeah. How's the show?
Oh, Dragon Ash show!
Come on! Come on, yeah! Oh, 行くぞ！
Come on! Come on, yeah! Oh, let's go!
Turn up radio そう 今日も聞こえるよ
Turn up the radio, yes, I can hear it today too
風に揺られ流れるStereo
Stereo flowing, swayed by the wind
肩で刻む軽快なRhythm
A cheerful rhythm tapped out on my shoulders
想いをのっけて届けるよRhyme
Rhymes carrying my feelings to deliver to you
よく晴れた空の真下 僕らは遥かな未来目指しました
Right beneath the clear blue sky, we aimed for a distant future
Master key 握り締め出発 雑踏の中 Kick down 一発
Grip the master key tight and set off, one kick down in the middle of the crowd
今想う闘いの日々
Now I think back to those days of struggle
感謝するごとに溢れ出す慈悲
With every bit of gratitude, compassion overflows
しのぎを削ったあの攻防戦
That fierce battle where we clashed swords
今なお続くここは最前線
Even now it continues, here on the front line
父から得た揺るぎない誇り
The unwavering pride I got from my father
母がくれた大きないたわり
The great kindness my mother gave me
キミにもらう温かいぬくもり
The warm comfort I receive from you
明日への糧に生き抜くために
As nourishment for tomorrow, in order to survive
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it
You makes me happy, when sky's gray
You make me happy, when the sky is gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
俺は東京生まれ HIP HOP育ち
I was born in Tokyo, raised on hip hop
悪そうな奴は大体友達
Bad-looking guys are generally my friends
悪そうな奴と大体同じ
Generally the same as bad-looking guys
裏の道歩き見てきたこの街
I've seen this city while walking the back streets
渋谷 六本木 そう思春期も早々に
Shibuya, Roppongi, early in my adolescence
これにぞっこんに
I fell in love with this
カバンなら置き放してきた高校に
Left my bag behind at high school
マジ親に迷惑かけた本当に
Really caused trouble for my parents
だが時は経ち 今じゃ雑誌のカヴァー
But time passed, now I'm on a magazine cover
そこらじゅうで幅きかす DON DADA
Don dada, making my presence felt everywhere
マイク掴んだらマジで No.1
Once I grab the mic, I'm truly number one
東京代表トップランカーだ
Tokyo representative, top ranker
そうこの地この国に生を授かり
Born in this land, this country
Jahに無敵の マイク預かり
Jah entrusted me with an invincible mic
仲間たち 親たち ファンたちに今日も
Today, too, to my friends, parents, and fans
感謝して進む 荒れたオフロード
I thank them as I advance on this rough off-road
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it
You makes me happy, when sky's gray
You make me happy when skies are gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
Yo, mic check 1, 2, uh
日出ずる国に僕ら生まれ育ち
Born and raised in the land where the sun rises
今こうして踏みしめる大地
Now treading the earth this way
常に開く新しいPage
Always opening a new page
旅に出よう それぞれのStage
Let's go on a journey, to each our own stage
ここに綴る歓びと感謝
Spelling out joy and gratitude here
共に奏でる真の理解者
True understanding playing together
つつみ隠さず時代を描写
Describing the era without hiding anything
Pressureはねのけて乱反射
Reflecting pressure away
注ぎ込もう 溢れ出す感情
Pouring in overflowing emotions
いつの日にも絶やさない愛情
Affection that never fades any day
ひるむことなく飛び込む戦場
Battlefield where I dive in without flinching
枯れることなく咲く百合の紋章
Emblem of the lily that blooms without withering
やさしい風ぬける昼下がり
Afternoon with a gentle breeze passing through
虹がのぞいたこんな雨上がり
Rainbow appeared after this rain
陽の光映した水たまり
Water puddle reflecting the sunlight
日々の歓びここに賛美
Daily joy, praise is here
ノエル様的な！
In Noel-sama's style!
この胸の高鳴りを
Putting the throbbing of this chest
歌にのせて
into a song
日々ここにあるもの
Feeling what is here every day
この手に感じて
with these hands
I got sound, I got feel, I got beautiful days
I got song, I got love, I got grateful days
I got it
You makes me happy, when sky's gray
You make me happy when skies are gray
Darling, my darling
Thank you father, mother and my friend
ルパン
Lupin
ルパン！
Lupin!
ルパン
Lupin
ルパン！
Lupin!
ルパン・ザ・ファイヤー
Lupin the Fire
Let me show you my everything
夢のこのファンタジーを見てな
Watch this dream fantasy
今こそ走る時なんだ (It's show time)
It's time to run now (It's show time)
そこで見ててよワンマンショー
Watch me there, a one-man show
これぐらいの試練じゃ足んないよ
This level of ordeal isn't enough
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない
What I want isn't things
I steal your heart
Listen!
Party people! 僕は人生駆け上がる猛スピード
Party people! I'm racing through life at high speed
まるでスキーの直滑降
Like a straight descent in skiing
核弾頭
A warhead
決めたことには頑固
Stubborn about what I've decided
ゆっくり生きる術なんて知らない
I don't know the trick to living slowly
ここはステージ遠慮は要らない
This is a stage, no need to be reserved
やることはやりますわ
I'll do what I'm supposed to do
高みの山目指せ
Aim for the mountain at the height
Put your hands up in the air!
それを見つめる君はセクシー
You who watch that, you're sexy
甘くとろけるまるでチェルシー
Melting sweetly, just like Chelsea
手櫛で髪掻きあげる様
The way you brush your hair back with your fingers
僕にとっての女王様
My very own queen...
そんなあなたを今夜抱きしめる
Tonight, I'll hold you close,
and 熱い唇をいただく
And receive your hot lips,
そして何よりも欲しいのよ
And more than anything, I want it,
あなたの心 狂おしいほど
Your heart, enough to drive me mad.
It's a party night
Dancin' with us
Everybody don't stop dance
Everybody, don't stop dancing,
Let's go, just do it!
茨の道だろうが
Even if it's a thorny road,
凍てつく夜だろうが
Even if it's a freezing night,
不可能が可能になるさ
The impossible will become possible,
君と二人で Lupin the Fire!
With just the two of us, Lupin the Fire!
だからそう だから誰も手にした事ないお宝
So, that's why, that's why, a treasure that nobody has ever laid hands on...
もらう 狙った獲物は逃がさない
...I will take. I never let a targeted prey escape,
それがなんだろうと大泥棒
No matter what it is, I'm a master thief.
先の先まで計算たてて
Calculating far ahead,
瞬時にひらめく名案
An excellent idea instantly flashes,
そして「あっ！」と思ったらもう居ない
And when you think 'Ah!', I'm already gone.
もはや芸術ばりの盗みの美学
It's already a beauty of stealing, like art.
Put your hands up in the air!
Let me show you my everything
夢のこのファンタジー見てな
Behold this fantasy of a dream.
今こそ走る時なんだ It's show time!
Now is the time to run, it's show time!
そこで見ててよワンマンショー
Watch me right there, my one-man show!
これぐらいの試練じゃ足んないよ
An ordeal of this level isn't enough,
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない I steal your heart
What I want isn't an object, I steal your heart.
絶対に逃がさん！
I absolutely won't let you escape!
無駄な抵抗はやめて大人しくお縄に就け！ルパン！
Give up this futile resistance and surrender quietly! Lupin!
逃がさんぞー！
I won't let you get away!
誰かが居ないと張り合いがない
There's no competition if nobody is here,
相手が居てこそ間違いがない
With an opponent, there's no mistake.
身近にゃ素敵なライバル
A wonderful rival close by,
競い合い互いにハイになる
Competing with each other, we both get high.
ファイナルステージだ天王山
It's the final stage, the showdown,
お前と勝負 of 演奏さ
A musical performance battle with you.
マジで今夜はサシで どっちが勝っても文句はナシで
Seriously tonight, just the two of us, whoever wins, no complaints!
Put your hands up in the air!
ワルサー使いこなす僕はワルさ
Mastering the Walther, I'm bad,
曲がったこと嫌いプラスアルファ
Hating twisted things, plus alpha.
ラップマスター ジェダイも目じゃない
Rap master, even Jedi can't match,
しかし可愛い女にも目がない
But I also have a soft spot for cute girls.
Oh baby それは演技？ or 本気？
Oh baby, is that acting? Or for real?
僕は君に一本気
I'm single-minded for you.
一本道走り続けます
I'll keep running down this single-track path,
空へ飛ばす 今日から明日
Flying into the sky, from today to tomorrow.
It's a party night
Dancin' with us
Everybody don't stop dance
Everybody, don't stop dancing,
Let's go, just do it!
茨の道だろうが
Even if it's a thorny road,
凍てつく夜だろうが
Even if it's a freezing night,
不可能が可能になるさ
The impossible will become possible,
君と二人で Lupin the Fire!
With just the two of us... Lupin the Fire!
Let me show you my everything
夢のこのファンタジーを見てな
Behold this fantasy of a dream.
今こそ走る時なんだ It's show time!
Now is the time to run, it's show time!
そこで見ててよワンマンショー
Watch me right there, my one-man show!
これぐらいの試練じゃ足んないよ
An ordeal of this level isn't enough,
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない
What I want isn't an object,
あなたのハート
But your heart.
愛すべき仲間や家族がいる
I have precious friends and family,
信念やプライドを曲げずに貫くべし！
I must stick to my beliefs and pride without bending!
Lupin the fire...
Let me show you my everything
眩しい眼差しをうけて
Basking in your dazzling gaze,
君のために今日を捨てるよ
For you, I will throw away today,
It's show time!
世界で一人の最愛の君自身に 気持ちを伝えたいよ
To the one and only, most beloved you, I want to convey my feelings.
僕が欲しいのは物じゃない あなたのハート
What I want isn't an object, but your heart.
普段はとぼけた三枚目
Usually a silly clown,
やるときゃ誰より真剣で
But when I act, I'm more serious than anyone.
頼りになるいざという時
Reliable when it really counts,
こうなりたい 誰が見ても素敵
I want to be like this, looking wonderful to anyone.
知性備えたスーパーマン
An intellectual superman,
横にはお決まりスーパーウーマン
With the usual superwoman by my side.
残り二小節ラストスパート
Two bars left, the last spurt,
憧れの男 Lupin the Third
The man of my dreams, Lupin the Third!
獲物は確かにいただいたぜ
I have indeed taken the prize.
はい！ということで、グレイトフルデイズとルパン・ザ・ファイヤーを2曲続けて聴いていただきました！
Yes! And with that, you just heard two songs in a row: Grateful Days and Lupin the Fire!
グレイトフルデイズはですね、えーっと、男性二人と女性一人の曲なんですけど、
So, Grateful Days is originally a song for two males and one female,
女性のところはね、絶対アズちゃんが良いってことでアズちゃん、
and I absolutely wanted Azu-chan for the female part, so Azu-chan is there.
で、ラップパートはもう、ノエルちゃんの顔しか浮かばなかったのでノエルちゃんにお願いしました！
As for the rap part, only Noel-chan's face came to mind, so I asked Noel-chan to do it!
二人ともありがとうー！
Thank you so much, you two!
でね、ルパンの映像が流れてみんなびっくりしたんじゃない？ころねもびっくりした！
And during Lupin, those visuals popped up, so wasn't everyone surprised? I was surprised too!
で、今日のハッシュタグは、もうね、7周年だって、すごいよね。
So, today's hashtag, it's already our 7th anniversary, which is amazing.
この上のハッシュタグ「#戌神ころね7周年」で、ぜひいっぱい呟いてください。スクショも大丈夫だよ！
Please tweet a lot with the hashtag above: #InugamiKorone7thAnniversary. Screenshots are fine too!
ね、ここのステージ。なんか今日は違った感じだけど、ここはどこなんでしょうか？
You see, this stage. It feels a bit different today, but where are we?
どこ？
Where?
イヌバレー！
Inu Valley!
素敵。今日はイヌバレーから、えー、すべてお送りしますので、よろしくお願いします。
Wonderful. Today, we'll be bringing everything to you from Inu Valley, so please look forward to it.
って思ったんだけどさ、なんか、画面小さくない？って思ってるよね、リスナーさん。
But thinking about it, isn't the screen a bit small? That's what you listeners are thinking, right?
ころねもちょっと思ったので、ちょっとね、
I thought so too, so...
あ、ちょっと待って！
Ah, wait a second!
なんか、縮まってる！縮まってる！
It's shrinking! It's shrinking!
やめて！やばい、やばい！
Stop! Oh no, oh no!
つぶれちゃうよ、これ！
I'm going to get crushed!
ちょっと押して、今は令和なのでね、画面を広く使いたいので、
Let me push it back. Since this is the Reiwa era, I want to use a wider screen, so...
あっち行け！
go away!
もうちょっとあっち行け！
Go away a bit more!
もうちょっと！
A bit more!
おけおけおけ。こっちは？
Okay, okay, okay. How about this side?
あっち行け！
Go away!
え、そんなころねと居たいの？おいで。
What, do you want to be with me that much? Come here.
ホントに来るんじゃねぇよ！
Don't actually come!
Don't actually come over here!
いくよ、早く！
Let's go, hurry!
あ、いた。
Ah, there it is.
あ、いたね。何だったんだろうね。
Ah, there it is. Wonder what that was.
ということで、
So anyway...
あ、なんか！
Oh, look!
なんか落ちてきたよ！
Something's falling!
花びらかな？これ。
Is this a flower petal?
こっちから降ってきた？
Did it fall from over here?
ちょっと行ってみよう！
Let's go check it out!
さくら / ケツメイシ
[Song: Sakura / Ketsumeishi]
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
Amongst the scattering of the cherry blossoms, forgotten memories and...
君の声が戻ってくる
...your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風 あの頃のままで
The spring wind doesn't stop blowing, just like back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
The fleeting scent from when the wind blew through your hair, fluttering it...
淡い香り戻ってくる
...comes back to me.
二人約束した あの頃のままで
Just like back then, when we made a promise.
ヒュルリーラ ヒュルリーラ
Hyururiira, hyururiira...
...hyururiira, hyururiira...
ヒュルリーラ ヒュルリーラ
...hyururiira, hyururiira.
さくら散りだす 思い出す 意味なく
The cherry blossoms start to scatter, and I remember.
灯り出す あの頃また気になる
A light turns on, and again I think about back then.
変わらない香り 景色 風
The scents, scenery, wind, none have changed.
違うのは君がいないだけ
The thing that's different is that you're not here.
ここに立つと甦る
I stand here, and it's all resurrected.
こみ上げる記憶 読み返す
The memories fill me, I re-read them.
春風に舞う長い髪
Long hair fluttering in the spring wind...
たわいないことでまた騒いだり
...acting silly and having fun again.
さくら木の真下 語り明かした
We talked all night long beneath the cherry blossom trees.
思い出は 俺輝いた証だ
Memories are my shining proof of that.
さくら散る頃 出会い別れ
When the cherry blossoms scatter, hellos and goodbyes.
それでも ここまだ変わらぬままで
Yet here, none of that has changed.
咲かした芽 君離した手
Buds have bloomed, you let go of my hand.
いつしか別れ 交したね
Before I knew it, goodbye mixed itself in.
さくら舞う季節に取り戻す
In the season when the cherry blossoms scatter...
あの頃そして君呼び起こす
...I'm going to take back those times and call you to life.
花びら舞い散る 記憶舞い戻る
The petals scatter, the memories scatter and return.
気付けばまたこの季節で 君との想い出に誘われ
Before I know it, I'm seduced by my memories with you in this season.
心の扉たたいた でも手をすり抜けた花びら
I knocked on the door of your heart, but the petals slipped through my fingers.
初めて分かった 俺若かった
For the first time I understood, I was young.
この場所来るまで 分からなかったが保存
I didn't understand until I got to this place.
此処だけは今も何故 運命のように香る風
Why, in this place, does the wind smell like fate?
暖かい陽の光がこぼれる 目を閉じればあの日に戻れる
The warm sunlight spills down; when I close my eyes, I can go back to that day.
いつしか君の面影は 消えてしまうよ 何処かへ
Before I know it, your face disappears somewhere.
あの日以来 景色変わらない
Since then, the scenery hasn't changed.
散りゆく花びらは語らない
The scattering petals don't speak.
さくらの下に響いた 君の声今はもう
Your voice echoes beneath the cherry blossoms, now still.
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
Amongst the scattering of the cherry blossoms, forgotten memories and...
君の声が戻ってくる
...your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風 あの頃のままで
The spring wind doesn't stop blowing, just like back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
The fleeting scent from when the wind blew through your hair, fluttering it...
淡い香り戻ってくる
...comes back to me.
二人約束した あの頃のままで
Just like back then, when we made a promise.
ヒュルリーラ ヒュルリーラ
Hyururiira, hyururiira...
...hyururiira, hyururiira.
そっと僕の肩に 舞い落ちたひとひらの花びら
A petal softly falls onto my shoulder.
手に取り 目をつむれば君が傍にいる
When I take it in my hand and close my eyes, you're by my side.
さくら舞い散る中に忘れた記憶と
Amongst the scattering of the cherry blossoms, forgotten memories and...
君の声が戻ってくる
...your voice come back to me.
吹き止まない春の風 あの頃のままで
The spring wind doesn't stop blowing, just like back then.
君が風に舞う髪かき分けた時の
The fleeting scent from when the wind blew through your hair, fluttering it...
淡い香り戻ってくる
...comes back to me.
二人約束した あの頃のままで
Just like back then, when we made a promise.
ヒュルリーラ ヒュルリーラ
Hyururiira, hyururiira...
...hyururiira, hyururiira...
ヒュルリーラ ヒュルリーラ
...hyururiira, hyururiira.
花びら舞い散る 記憶舞い戻る
The petals scatter, the memories scatter and return.
花びら舞い 散る 記憶舞い戻る
Cherry blossom petals dance and scatter, memories return.
花びら舞い 散る
Cherry blossom petals dance and scatter...
タイムマシーンにのって
[Song: Riding on a Time Machine]
人はこれって時にどうしても 「時間を戻せたら」とかいうね
When times get tough, people always say, "If only I could turn back time."
でも誰も直せないよ 治せないんだな
But no one can change it, they just can't fix it.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's always been that way, so I guess it can't be helped.
きっと先は深くって不安定
The road ahead is surely deep and unstable,
でも お行儀よくちゃ つまんないね
but being too well-behaved is just boring.
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
If I could jump into a time machine
トラベラーになれたら
and become a time traveler...
箱の中の猫を思っても
Even if I think about the cat in the box,
後悔だけが胸を焦がして
only regret burns in my chest,
いつもあの猜疑心が遮るんだわ
and that skepticism always gets in the way.
昔からそうだし まぁしょうがないね
It's always been that way, so I guess it can't be helped.
きっと先は深くって不安定
The road ahead is surely deep and unstable,
でも お行儀よくちゃ つまんないね
but being too well-behaved is just boring.
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
If I could jump into a time machine
トラベラーになれたら
and become a time traveler...
どこをどうやってもね
No matter where I go or what I do,
時間ってのは戻せない
time is something we can't turn back.
レンズ越し未来にめがけて
Aimed at the future through the lens,
ピースサイン伝えてる 今のとこいい調子
sending a peace sign. Doing good so far.
青春の1ページも
Even a single page of my youth...
たったの1ページで
...is just a single page.
きっと先は深くて不安定
Surely the path ahead is deep and unstable
でも お行儀よくちゃ つまんないね
But being well-behaved is just boring
タイムマシーンに乗り込んで
Hop into the time machine
トラベラーになれたら
If only I could become a traveler
Done
[Forever Young]
シボレーのドアを蹴り開けて街に飛び出した俺んた
Kicking open the door of the Chevy and heading out into the streets
暴力 酒に女 音楽 中指立てる大人の仮面にゃ
Violence, booze, women, music; flipping off the masks of adults
さぁ踊ろう 「今日」という日を生き急ぐメンバー
Let's dance, members rushing through this day called 'today'
足りねぇか？ Little louder! 欲望渦巻く路上が現場
Not enough? Little louder! The swirling street of desire is our stage
いつだってそうだろ？ ブルハ 尾崎 永ちゃんが教科書
It's always been like that, right? Blue Hearts, Ozaki, Echan are our textbooks
くたばるまで格好つけてぇ 誓ったよあの放課後
We swore to look cool until we drop, back then after school
俺らピーターパン 「またいつか」なんて言っちゃいかん<
We're Peter Pan, we shouldn't say 'maybe some other time'
嘲笑っとる大人に言ってやらぁ 人生はたったの一回だ
Tell those mocking adults, life only happens once!
胸の奥底 初期衝動
Deep in our chest, the primal urge
見て見ぬフリ No, No
Turning a blind eye, no, no
夢追い笑われ 傷だらけでギラつく My way
Chasing dreams, being laughed at, glittering on my way full of scars
Go on! You should know who we are Forever Young
Hey! Just next to me from now 大切なことは魂の状態
Hey! Just next to me from now, the important thing is the state of your soul
Forever Young
Hey! It's your turn next time from here 「あの日始めれば良かった」
Hey! It's your turn next time from here, 'I wish I had started that day'
その次の始めるべき時は今
The next best time to start is now
高笑いする都会の喧騒 ウケ狙いならば振り向けれんぞ
The roaring din of the city, we won't look back for cheap laughs
何連呼？忘れろ？夢流した便所見下ろしてきやがる摩天楼
How many calls? Forget it? The skyscrapers looking down on the toilet where dreams were flushed
Oh まるで勝新みたく破天荒 伝説へとアテンド
Daring like Shintaro Katsu, attending to the legend
怖にゃあ怖にゃあてその程度
If you're scared, it's only to that extent
捨てろ負け惜しみ 過去の栄光
Throw away your sour grapes and past glory
永遠なんぞはねぇて いつか天へ召され ペンで
There's no such thing as eternity, we'll be summoned to heaven someday
書き殴ったこの魂は2PACみたく誰かの心を通過
This soul scribbled down will pass through someone's heart like 2Pac
なぁ何か忘れちゃねぇか 人生まるで映画 皆がエンターテイナー
Hey, didn't you forget something? Life is like a movie, everyone is an entertainer
思い出せ思想は現実化する 誰がHighway飛ばすBentayga
Remember, thoughts become reality, who's speeding down the highway in a Bentayga?
胸の奥底 初期衝動
Deep in our chest, the primal urge
見て見ぬフリ No, No
Turning a blind eye, no, no
夢追い笑われ 傷だらけでギラつく My way
Chasing dreams, being laughed at, glittering on my way full of scars
Go on! You should know who we are Forever Young
Hey! 俺達は今日だって 若気の至りのような夢を追いかけて来た
Hey! Even today we've been chasing dreams like the rashness of youth
Forever Young
Hey! 変わるはずなんてない さぁ至ってやろうぜ!
Hey! There's no way it'll change, so let's reach for it!
今日は残された人生で一番若い日だろ
Today is the youngest day of the rest of your life
半端な覚悟ならドブに捨てな (永遠)
If your determination is half-hearted, throw it in the ditch (Eternity)
往生際が悪いテメー笑い飛ばし誇れBetter days
Laugh off your bad sportsmanship and take pride in better days
まだ終わらない 終わらせやしない 燃え尽きるまで (永遠)
It's not over yet, we won't let it end, until we burn out (Eternity)
まだ終わらない 終わらせやしない くたばるまで (永遠)
It's not over yet, we won't let it end, until we drop dead (Eternity)
Forever Young もう夢を追いかけ 本気になった心は
Forever Young, the heart that has chased dreams and got serious
自分の指図も受けない
won't even take orders from itself
Forever Young Hey! その思いから逃れられないなら
Forever Young, hey! If you can't escape that feeling,
自ら向かうだけ
just head toward it yourself
終わらせやしない 燃え尽きるまで (永遠)
We won't let it end, until we burn out (Eternity)
まだ終わらない 終わらせやしない くたばるまで (永遠)
It's not over yet, we won't let it end, until we drop dead (Eternity)
まだ終わらない まだ終わらない Forever Young (Forever Young)
It's not over yet, it's not over yet, Forever Young (Forever Young)
そう 今日という日は お前に残された人生の一番若い日
That's right, today is the youngest day of the rest of your life
イェーイ！
Yay!
マリン、来てくれてありがとう！
Marine, thank you for coming!
呼んでくれてありがとう！イェーイ！
Thank you for inviting me! Yay!
いや、マジこのForever Youngって曲をマリンと一緒に歌いたかったの、Forever Youngって曲をね。
No, seriously, I really wanted to sing this song 'Forever Young' with Marine.
あー、それはマリンがおばさんにならないように？
Ah, so that Marine won't become an old lady?
そう、もうForeverのYoungだって言うのを、言ってやるっていうね！
Yeah, to tell you that you're Forever Young!
そうだね、永遠にね。ヤング、うちらは。
That's right, eternally. We are young.
みんな、みんな、Forever Young。
Everyone, everyone, Forever Young.
悩んだ？
Were you worried?
うーん
Yeah.
でもマリン今日はね、今日はね
But Marine is, you see, today...
え？
Huh?
え、後ろ見て！
Look behind you!
演奏してくれてる！
They're playing for us!
気まずいよ。
This is awkward.
今日はね、演奏してくれてるの、みんなが。
Today, everyone is playing for us!
乗ってる、乗ってる。乗ってるよ。
They're grooving, they're grooving!
乗ってるでしょ？え、ど、どの子と写真撮りたい？
Right? So, which one do you want to take a photo with?
え、そんな、え、1人だけみたいな、そんななんか...
Huh? To choose just one, that's kind of...
いや、2人選んでいい、2人選んでいい。
No, you can choose two, you can choose two!
かわいそうじゃん、選ばれなかったの。
It'd be sad for the ones who weren't chosen.
2人選ぼう、2人選ぼう。
Let's choose two, let's choose two.
俺もう、コロネすきが、なんか、3...
For me, the Koronesuki are like, 3...
いいよ、じゃあマリンが選ぶね。
Okay, then Marine will choose.
あ、マリンが、え、え、選んで。
Oh, Marine, please choose.
そうそう。じゃ、最初は...
Right. Well, first...
あ、ちょっと待って。
Ah, wait a second.
最初は...
First is...
待って、写して、後ろ。
Wait, show the background.
みんな下向いて。
Everyone, look down!
細犬さん？
Hosoinu-san?
かわいい、かわいい、かわいい。
Cute, cute, cute!
じゃ、まず細犬と写真撮ろっか。
Well, let's take a photo with Hosoinu first.
かわいいよ、細犬。
You're cute, Hosoinu.
こっちおいで、マリン、こっち、こっちね。
Come over here. Marine is here, here.
はい、細犬です。
Here is Hosoinu.
えーと、細犬はギターかな？
Uh, is Hosoinu on guitar?
ギターですか？細犬ちゃん。
Is it the guitar, Hosoinu-chan?
ベロの色が...
The color of the tongue...
乾いてる？ベロ。
Is the tongue dry?
ベロ乾いて、ちょっと吸い込んでるんだけど、ベロの...
The tongue is dry, it's a bit sucked in, but...
これ乾いてる。
This is dry.
うん、乾いてる。触らないでね。
Yeah, it's dry. Don't touch it.
ごめんね、いっぱい触って。
Sorry for touching you so much.
え、次、誰がいい？
Who do you want next?
かわいい。あと1人、あと1人。
Cute! One more, one more.
じゃあ、太犬？
Then, Futoinu?
太犬ね。
Futoinu, then.
はい、太犬はドラムです。かわいい！
Okay, Futoinu is on drums. Cute!
でかい！
Huge!
ドゥンドゥンドゥンドゥン。
Boom, boom, boom, boom!
かわいいね。
It's cute.
あ、ベロの色がちょっと明るい。
Ah, the color of the tongue is a bit bright.
細犬より。
More than Hosoinu's.
撮った？みんな、撮った？
Did you take it? Did everyone take it?
イェーイ、撮った？
Yay, did you take it?
かわいい！
Cute!
オッケーだね。
We're good.
うん、オッケー。
Yeah, we're good.
え、じゃ、最後さ、2人でも撮ろうよ、2人でも。
Let's take a photo of just the two of us at the end.
あ、そうだね、2人でも撮ろう、2人でも。
Ah, right, let's take one together.
2人で撮って。
Take a photo of the two of us.
え？
Huh?
ちょっと...
Wait...
あ、あ、ごめんごめん、やっぱりじゃあね、やっぱり撮りたいみたいだから。
Ah, sorry, sorry. It seems he really wants to take a photo.
あ、やっぱりね。
Ah, I knew it.
コロネすきいたもんね。
There's a Koronesuki there.
撮りますか。
Shall we take one?
コロネすき、ころさん好き？
Koronesuki, do you like Koro-san?
好き？ころさん好き？
Do you like her? Do you like Koro-san?
あ、よかった。え、マリンも好き？
Ah, thank goodness. Do you like Marine too?
間に入ろう。
Let me get in between.
なんでだよ！
Why?!
コロネすきなのにころさんの隣に立てない気分どう？
How does it feel to be a Koronesuki but unable to stand next to Koro-san?
嬉しい？マリンが隣で。
Are you happy Marine is next to you?
嬉しくない...
Not happy...
本当は好きなの。
He actually likes her.
やめろ、やめろよ！
Stop it, stop it!
ダメ、もうダメ。帰るよ、もう。
No, that's enough. I'm going back.
はい、帰ろう。
Okay, let's go back.
はい、今日はね、今日のバンドメンバーがいましたけれど。ですね。
Yes, today we had our band members here.
ええ。
Yes.
はい、え、マリンとも最後撮りたい？
Okay, do you want to take a photo with Marine at the end?
あ、撮ろう撮ろう撮ろう。
Ah, let's take one!
せっかくね。フォーエバーヤングだから、今日は。
Might as well. Since we are Forever Young today.
マイク、マリン...
The mic, Marine...
マイク、間違えちゃってるけどさ。
You got the mic wrong.
マイクね。うん、いいよいいよ。
Oh, the mic. Yeah, that's fine.
でかい声で喋ると拾うから。
Speak louder so it picks up.
でかい声で...
Speak louder...
撮れた？
Did we get it?
いけてる？
Is it working?
太犬？
Futoinu?
中心として写って...
It's captured as the center...
え、かわいく撮れたね。
Ah, we got a cute photo.
うん。ありがとう、マリン。
Yeah. Thank you, Marine.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
で、ちょっと次の曲があるから行くけど。次の曲。
Well, I have to go because the next song is starting.
うん、次の曲。
Yeah, the next song.
1人で帰れる？
Can you go back alone?
おお、ええ、そう...うん、大丈夫。
Oh, uh, yeah, I'm fine.
じゃあ、バンドメンバーのことよろしく。
Well then, take care of the band members.
え？
Huh?
じゃあ、マリン、バイバイ。
Well then, bye-bye, Marine.
よろしくって何よ？よろしく。
"Take care" of what? Take care...
え、どんなムードなの、これ？あ、え？
Huh? What kind of mood is this? Ah, eh?
あ、みんな、あ、え、どうして？みんな、次の曲だよ。
Ah, everyone, eh, why? Everyone, next song!
ラララ...
Lalala...
Hey! Hey! Hey! Hey!
サボり方とか 甘え方とか
How to slack off, how to baby myself...
逃げ方とか言い訳の仕方とか
How to run away, how to make excuses...
やっと覚えてきた 身につけてきた
I finally learned them, I acquired them,
柔らかい頭
my flexible mind.
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方
How to act cool, how to get ahead of myself...
腹の据え方 良い年のこき方
How to steel my resolve, how to grow old gracefully...
脂のりに乗った 濁った目をした
Full of fat, with muddy eyes...
だらしない身体
this sloppy body.
嫌われ方や 宥められ方や
How to be disliked, how to be pacified...
アットマーク 叱られ方とか 綺麗なぶつかり方
How to be scolded, and how to clash gracefully.
もっと覚えたいことが山のようにある
There are mountains of things I still want to learn.
のびしろしかないわ
I've got nothing but room to grow!
わっわっわ のびしろしかないわ
Woah, woah, woah, nothing but room to grow!
のびしろしかないわ
Nothing but room to grow!
俺らまだのびしろしかないわ
We've still got nothing but room to grow!
悪者扱いされてきた街で
In the town where I was treated like a bad guy,
悪者扱いされてきた大人へ
to the adult who was treated like a bad guy...
変わりゆく俺 鏡の中へ
Transforming myself into the mirror...
yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
去る者は追わない 弾くとこ弾いて
I won't chase those who leave, I play where I should...
丸く収めた 軽くあしらって
Settling things smoothly, brushing them off lightly...
鏡の中で笑ってるお前
You, smiling in the mirror...
覆う気合を誓ったたったの三文字で
Swearing my motivation with just three characters.
日々重くなる足取りで
With steps growing heavier day by day,
自分の歩幅で完走してる
I'm finishing the race at my own pace.
かますとこかます 任すとこ任す
Pulling off what I must, leaving what I must...
割と適当な段取りで
With relatively sloppy planning.
やっと分かってきたかも
I think I might finally be figuring out...
このポンコツの操縦の仕方
how to navigate this piece of junk.
19の時のついに来たかより
Better than the 'it finally came' feeling at 19,
もっと清々しい気持ち
a much more refreshing feeling.
隅田川にかかる
Spanning the Sumida River...
勝鬨橋を渡る
I cross the Kachidoki Bridge.
左手にスカイツリー
On my left, Sky Tree...
右手に東京タワー
On my right, Tokyo Tower...
俺はその真ん中
I'm right in the middle.
サボり方とか 甘え方とか
How to slack off, how to baby myself...
逃げ方とか言い訳の仕方とか
How to run away, how to make excuses...
やっと覚えてきた 身につけてきた
I finally learned them, I acquired them,
柔らかい頭
my flexible mind.
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方
How to act cool, how to get ahead of myself...
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方 腹の据え方 良い年のこき方
How to look cool, act cocky, stay firm, and age gracefully
脂の乗りに乗った 濁った目した だらし無い身体
A slovenly body in its prime with listless eyes
幸せの体感速度は早くなるばかり
My perceived speed of happiness only gets faster
傷が癒えていく速度は遅くなるばかり
The speed at which my wounds heal only gets slower
他人にお節介をしないのが今の俺の強み
Not expecting anything from others is my current strength
手空いてでも進める距離なら行く 騙し騙し
Even if I have to turn back, if it's a distance I can cover, I'll go, coaxing myself along
身の程を知る程に胸を張り いつも通り
The more I know my place, the more I puff out my chest, as always
でも時にしたって良い背伸び やっと大人げないができる歳
But sometimes it's fine to reach high, finally at an age where I can be childish
小さな枠組みただの数字 縛られずにでも腹括り
Small frameworks, just numbers, unbound but resolved
あの日の俺が立ち止まる ほどにデカくそびえ立つ
Towering so high that the me of that day would stop in his tracks
隅田川にかかる勝鬨橋を渡る
Crossing the Kachidoki Bridge over the Sumida River
重なるスカイツリー 東京タワーと真ん中の頼りない背中
Overlapping Sky Tree and Tokyo Tower, with my unreliable back in the middle
サボり方とか甘え方とか逃げ方と言い訳の仕方とか
How to slack off, how to depend on others, how to run away and make excuses
やっと覚えてきた 身につけてきた 柔らかい頭
I've finally learned and acquired a flexible mind
カッコのつけ方 調子のこき方 腹の据え方 良い年のこき方
How to look cool, act cocky, stay firm, and age gracefully
脂の乗りに乗った 濁った目した だらし無い身体
A slovenly body in its prime with listless eyes
嫌われ方や慕われ方や叱り方とか綺麗なぶつかり方
How to be disliked, adored, scolded, and how to clash beautifully
覚えたいことが山のようにある のびしろしかないわ
There's a mountain of things I want to learn, I've got nothing but room to grow
のびしろしかないわ
Nothing but room to grow
俺たちまだのびしろしかないわ
We've still got nothing but room to grow
ばかまじめ
[Song: Bakamajime]
くだんない話と
Silly talk and...
うざったい貴様と
...annoying you...
なみなみの日々に
...are being poured...
注がれてく 怠いが溢れ出してく
...into ordinary days as laziness overflows
飯がまだ届かない
My food hasn't arrived yet
仕事は片付かない
My work isn't done
うだつの上がらない毎日にため息ばかり
Nothing but sighs in these unproductive days
でまたド派手にすっころび
And then I fall down spectacularly again
洗い立てのシャツにこぼすコーヒー
Spilling coffee on a freshly washed shirt
前のめりその姿勢だけは褒めて良し
At least praise my forward-leaning posture
肩落とす並木通り 増えた柄と差し色に
Slumping shoulders along tree-lined streets, adding patterns and accent colors
嗚呼 本当嫌んなる毎日だ
Ah, I'm really fed up with these days
やりたくないことやったって
Even if I do things I don't want to
嫌々早起きしたって
Or reluctantly wake up early
その分素敵な何かが
It's not like something wonderful...
訪れるとかそんなわけでもないのにさ
...will happen in return anyway
今日もまた頑張っちゃうよな
Yet here I am, working hard again today
がむしゃら以外知らないから
Because I don't know any other way than going reckless
不器用で意地っ張りで馬鹿真面目な僕らに幸あれ
May blessings be upon clumsy, stubborn, and stupidly honest us
重くなってきた荷物をちょっと置いて立ち止まり
Putting down my heavy load for a bit and stopping
昨日の事なんざ忘れちまえば同じ
If I just forget about yesterday, it's all the same
浴びるday light 羽根伸ばし
Basking in the daylight, stretching my wings
それか月夜にこっそりと吐き出してしまえば良い
Or quietly spitting it all out under the moonlight
でもその前にアレとコレの話
But before that, let's talk about this and that
そのためには先ずはソレを片し
To do that, first let's clean this up
って今何時？いやその前に
Wait, what time is it now? No, before that...
今日もなんだかんだ騒がしい毎度あり
Somehow today is noisy again, thank you for your business
1ヶ月くらい何にも考えずだらだらしていたいな
I want to laze around for about a month without thinking of anything
ゆっくり休んで遊んで眠っていたいなって
I want to rest up, play, and sleep, I think...
思う日もあるけれど
There are days I feel like that, but
やっとここまできたんだよ
We finally made it this far
ここじゃ終われないんだよ
We can't end it here
辛いきついもいつかは笑い話にできると信じてるんだほら
Believing that all the tough times will become a laughing matter someday, see?
今日もまた頑張っちゃうからさ
Because I'm going to work hard again today
がむしゃらに愛を歌うからさ
Because I'm going to sing about love recklessly
目一杯吸い込んだ空気 嗚呼本当素晴らしい毎日だ
Taking a deep breath of air, ah, what a truly wonderful daily life
やりたくないことやったって
Even if I do things I don't want to
嫌々早起きしたって
Or reluctantly wake up early
ほんの少しの幸せに触れるだけで全部全部ありに思えるんだ...
Just touching a tiny bit of happiness makes it all seem worth it
明日もまた頑張ってみようか がむしゃらに生きていくんだ
Shall we try our best again tomorrow? We'll live recklessly
不器用で意地っ張りで馬鹿真面目な僕らに幸あれ
May blessings be upon clumsy, stubborn, and stupidly honest us
do my thing do your thing
肩の力を抜いて柔軟に
Relax your shoulders and be flexible
do my thing do your thing
あと1ミリ背伸び
Stretching just one more millimeter
嗚呼本当嫌んなっちゃうよな
Ah, I really get fed up with it
それでも今を生きている
But we are still living in the present
不器用で意地っ張りで馬鹿真面目なあなたに幸あれ
May blessings be upon clumsy, stubborn, and stupidly honest you
Longiness
[Song Title: Longiness]
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable level of perfection + transparent imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても
Even if I struggle, wanting to be like him,
底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
I will sink like a bottomless swamp.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable level of perfection + transparent imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて
NickelBurn and set it on fire,
君の心に落とすimagination
dropping imagination into your heart.
ギリギリでフライできず地獄送りさ
Barely unable to fly, sent straight to hell.
君が飛べなかった理由を一つ教えたろうか
Shall I tell you one reason why you couldn't fly?
それは目の前のプロップスに心委ね
It's because you surrendered your heart to the props in front of you,
近道した結果誰かの後をつけてるだけだったからさ
took a shortcut, and ended up just following in someone else's footsteps.
未だわからないか 最初は気づいてた
Do you still not get it? I noticed at first.
知らぬふりして
Pretending not to know,
自分の道だと言い聞かせた
telling yourself it's your own path.
他は騙せないオリジナルを奏でないと
You can't fool anyone else; if you don't play something original,
過去の自分に足を引っ張られて退場
your past self will drag you down and you'll exit.
俺とお前との差は遺伝子レベル
The difference between you and me is at the genetic level.
俺を狂わせた父母祖父母には感謝してる
I'm grateful to my parents and grandparents who drove me crazy.
さらに磨き上げた自分自身にも感謝してる
I'm also grateful to my own self, whom I polished even further.
なのに何してる
And yet, what are you doing?
君差が離れてくうちに
While the gap between us widens...
絶望を感じどうせラップやめるよ
you'll feel despair and quit rapping anyway.
5年後いや4年後？これ、余命宣告
In 5 years, no, 4 years? This is a prognosis.
現状に満足して威張ってんの？
Are you showing off, satisfied with the status quo?
俺らは発展途上でもかっけえぞ
Even if we're still developing, we're cool!
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable level of perfection + transparent imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても
Even if I struggle, wanting to be like him,,og:
底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
I will sink like a bottomless swamp.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable level of perfection + transparent imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて
NickelBurn and set it on fire,
君の心に落とすimagination
dropping imagination into your heart.
恋焦がれた男達と時をかけた女達
Men who fell in love, and women who leapt through time.
上辺だけのお友達がお前の事甘やかす
Superficial friends spoil you.
命削り のらりくらり 情熱だけを注ぐ歌詞
Shaving off life, aimlessly pouring passion only into lyrics.
現実に頬濡らす 理想達が雨降らす
Cheeks wet with reality, ideals making it rain.
あれもカスでこれもカスで俺の歌詞で振り向かす
That's trash, this is trash, I'll make them turn around with my lyrics.
ウキになって無視したって知らぬ内に街を爬う
Even if you ignore it in high spirits, it crawls through the city unnoticed.
身体揺らし声を枯らしたって誰も聞いてない
Even if you shake your body and wither your voice, nobody's listening.
導かれて聴いてみても耳は糸を引いてない
Even if guided to listen, ears aren't pulled by strings.
今日と明日明日明後日も白紙の中あさって
Today, tomorrow, and the day after, searching inside a blank sheet.
思想すらも曲がってる だけど顔は笑ってる
Even thoughts are bent, but the face is smiling.
嘘だらけの肥溜めで のぼせるまで浸かって
Soaking in a cesspool full of lies until dizzy.
空に祈り捧げたって変えられるのは声だけ
Even if praying to the sky, only the voice can be changed.
何かあれば孤独気取りむしり取るかね
If something happens, posing as lonely, plucking money?
指で擦りめくり表あれば裏探すだけ
Rubbing and flipping with fingers, if there's a front, just looking for the back.
歯止め効かぬ無駄な愚痴も全て愛で砕けてる
Unstoppable useless grumbles are all shattered by love.
もうこんな歌詞は書きたくない 全部お前のせい
I don't want to write lyrics like this anymore, it's all your fault!
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable level of perfection + transparent imitation
あいつになりたくてもがいても
Even if I struggle, wanting to be like him,
底なし沼のように沈んでくよ
I will sink like a bottomless swamp.
リーズナブルな完成度＋スケスケまくりのimitation
Reasonable level of perfection + transparent imitation
NickelBurnして火つけて
NickelBurn and set it on fire,
君の心に落とすimagination
dropping imagination into your heart.
[チーム友達]
[Title: Team Tomodachi]
ち、ち、チーム友達
Te-Te-Team Tomodachi
チーム友達
Team Tomodachi
俺たち何？え？チーム友達
What are we? Huh? Team Tomodachi
関西 関東 西 東
Kansai, Kanto, West, East
北 南 チーム友達
North, South, Team Tomodachi
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
俺たち何？え？チーム友達
What are we? Huh? Team Tomodachi
お好み焼き
Okonomiyaki
食う鶴橋
Eating at Tsuruhashi
腹いっぱい
Full stomach
飯はうまい
The food is good
一人じゃ寂しいし
I'm lonely on my own, and...
電話きた
A call came
かけなおした
Called back
すぐ食いに
Going to eat right away
T-E-A-M T-O-M-O-D-A-C-H-I
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Tomodachi, Team Tomodachi
チーム友達 契り合い
Team Tomodachi, bonding together
契り交わし 飲んでる酒
Pledging bonds, drinking sake
契り 契り
Bonding, bonding
契ろう 契ろう
Let's bond, let's bond
契り 契り
Bonding, bonding
契ろう 契ろう
Let's bond, let's bond
チーム友達
Team Tomodachi
俺たち何？え？チーム友達
What are we? Huh? Team Tomodachi
関西 関東 西 東
Kansai, Kanto, West, East
北 南 チーム友達
North, South, Team Tomodachi
チーム友達
Team Tomodachi
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Friends, Team Friends
俺たち何？ 何ち？何？
What are we? What's that? What?
チーム友達 チーム友達
Team Friends, Team Friends
チーム友達！
Team Friends!
いぇーい！ よーよーよー！
Yeah! Yo yo yo!
ヤバい、柄悪くない？ヤバい！
This is bad, don't we look like thugs? Oh my!
うん、見えんの。あ、ごめん、見えんのよ。ね、ヤバいよね！
Yeah, you can see it... Ah, sorry, you can see it. Right? It's crazy!
おーい、柄が悪いぞー！
Hey, we look like thugs!
ちょっとね、この帽子のせいでね、ちょっとヤカラっぽくなっちゃうけどね。
Because of this cap, we look a bit like punks.
うん、ちょっとヤカラっぽくなっちゃうけどね。
Yeah, we look a bit like punks, though.
うううん、カッコいいじゃん！みこ、こんな格好いつかしてみてたかったんだよー！
No, but it's cool! Miko always wanted to try dressing like this!
でもこれ、バチくそ高いからこれ気をつけて。
But listen, this is crazy expensive, so be careful.
今日ね、来たらね、これ用意してあるんでって言われて、「えっ、何これ？」って。
Today when I arrived, they told me they had this prepared, and I was like, "Wait, what is this?"
重たいでしょ？ うん、重たい。でもカッコいい。
It's heavy, right? / Yeah, it's heavy. But it's cool.
あの、ロック・リーみたいになってるから、今うち等。 ロック・リー！
We're like Rock Lee right now. / Rock Lee!
おもりつけてるからね、今。
We've got weights on right now.
解き放たれたら、もっと動けるの？ そうそう。外したらね、いい感じになりますけど。
If we take them off, can we move even faster? / Exactly. If we take them off, we'll be super fast.
え、でも、ころさん、7周年おめでとうございます！
But anyway, Koro-san, happy 7th anniversary!
ありがとう！ありがとう。7周年なんだよ、ころね。 ねー、すごい！
Thank you! Thank you. It's my 7th anniversary! / Right? Amazing!
ね、すごいよね。え、待って、みこちゃんの衣装見て。
Right, it's amazing. Oh, wait, look at Miko-chan's outfit.
これ誕生日で着てたやつね！ はい、着てたやつね。可愛い！
This is the one you wore for your birthday! / Yes, the one I wore. It's so cute!
え、後ろも見せて、後ろも。ちょっとあの、今回用意してくれたこの装飾に、なんかマッチしてて...
Show me the back too, the back. / The accessories they prepared for this match it so well...
お揃いなんですけど。 メっちゃマッチしてます。
...it's like we're matching. / It matches perfectly.
え、でも、それでいうところねのこの衣装さ、ゲマズのイベントのやつじゃない？
But speaking of which, Korone, this outfit... Isn't this from the Gamers event?
そうそうそう！超超超超超ゲマズの衣装！ 可愛いじゃん！
Yes, yes, yes! The Cho-Cho-Cho-Cho-Cho Gamers outfit! / It's so cute!
みこちゃん、今日ね、これが初お披露目なんだ、この衣装の。
Miko-chan, today is actually the first time I'm revealing this outfit!
えっ！？これで！？ これでチーム友達でちょっと初... 初お披露目！
What?! In this?! / With "Team Tomodachi", this is the first... / First reveal!
初お披露目しちゃったんですけど。 え、いいじゃん、いいじゃん！可愛い。
I ended up revealing it for the first time like this. / Hey, that's great! It's so cute.
ちょっと、ちょっと短くない？ なんか、エッチじゃない？
Wait, isn't it a bit short? / Isn't it a bit sexy?
そうなん、ちょっとこれめっちゃ短いんだよね、大丈夫？ お尻丸見えじゃん！
Yeah, it's actually super short. Is it okay? / Your butt is totally visible!
こら！見せるんじゃないよ！ 大大丈夫かな？ しかもね、ころなんかさ...
Hey! Don't show it! / I wonder if it's okay. / And also, they told me...
めっちゃ胸がパツパツって言われてて、これ。 いや、なんかちょっとシワができてるもん、パツパツで。
...that my chest is super tight in this. / Yeah, there are actually some wrinkles because it's so tight.
弾け飛びそうだよ、なんか。 たぶんね、サイズが合ってないんだと思う。あ、でも、これくらいがいいですからね。
It looks like it's going to burst open. / I think the size might be wrong. But well, this much is just right.
え、写真撮ろう、写真！ 写真撮りたい！
Hey, let's take a picture! / I want to take a picture!
ちょっとアップめで撮りたいな。いい感じ、うん。 じゃあ、しゃがもう。
I want to take a close-up. Looks good, yeah. / Let's squat down then.
しゃがむか。よー！ よー！
Let's squat. Yo! / Yo!
あ、いいじゃん！ よーよー！スパイダーマンみたいになっちゃった。
Oh, this is great! / Yo, yo! I look like Spider-Man.
よーよー！
Yo, yo!
え、サングラスも取ってさ... あ、サングラス取るからね！
Hey, let's take off the sunglasses too... / Oh, we're taking them off!
よいしょ、よいしょ。ちょっと待ってね、みんなね。よいしょ。
Heave-ho, heave-ho. / Wait a moment, everyone. There we go.
行くよ！せーの... はい！
Here we go! One, two... / Cheese!
あ、いい感じ！ あ、アップめで撮れた。
Oh, that looks great! / Ah, we got a close-up.
アップめで撮りたい、いぇーい！ カメラをいただきましてね。あ、どう？
I want a close-up, yeah! / Let me hold the camera... How's this?
いぇーい！よー！撮れてる？ チーム友達。 チーム友達、俺たち何？
Yeah! Yo! Did you get it? / Team friends. / Team friends, what are we?
どこ歌ってんねん！ いぇーい！
Which part are you singing?! / Yeah!
でもさ、この曲選んでくれたの嬉しかったよ。
But you know, I was so happy you chose this song.
やっぱ「チーム友達」っていうぐらいの歌だから、友達と歌いたくて。
Since the song is literally called "Team Friends", I wanted to sing it with a friend.
だから、誰でもよかったんだけど、別に。友達だからみんな。 おい！
So, honestly, anyone would have been fine, since everyone is my friend. / Hey!
嘘、嘘！特に、特にみこみこと歌いたかった！
Just kidding, just kidding! Especially, I especially wanted to sing with Miko-miko!
ああ、なるほどね。チーム友達だからね、当たり前ちゃん！
Ah, I see. / Because we are team friends, of course!
チーム友達、いぇーい！
Team friends, yeah!
でも、ちょっとそろそろ、次の曲なんじゃないですか？
But, isn't it about time for the next song?
あ、そう、もうちょっとね、もうちょっとだけ続くのじゃよ、なんだけど。 エ、次どんな感じなの？
Oh right, there's actually a little bit more to go before that. / Oh, what is the next one like?
え、次はね、あの、パンツですね。え？パンツ？
Next is, well... "Pants". / Eh? Pants?
パンツ。 え？パンツ？
Pants. / Eh? Pants?
恥ずかしい。やめて、撮らないで。撮らないで！ 待って、待って。パンツって、この、穿いてるパンツってこと？
It's embarrassing. Stop, don't take pictures! Don't look! / Wait, wait. By "pants", do you mean the underwear we're wearing?
え、みこさん穿いてないの？ え？ みこさん穿いてないの？パンツ。
Wait, Miko-san, aren't you wearing any? / Eh? / Miko-san, aren't you wearing pants?
安心してください、穿いてますよ！穿いてる？ あ、よかった、じゃあ。
Please rest assured, I am wearing them! Are you? / Ah, thank goodness then.
え、ころねはまだ、これからなのよ、パンツ。 え？穿いてないってこと？
Wait, for Korone, it's actually coming up next... "Pants". / Eh? Meaning you're not wearing them right now?
ころねはちょっと、これからなの。 え？これから？ これから。
For Korone, it's just coming up next. / Eh? Next? / Next.
ごめん、みこみこ、これからだから、ころねパンツ。 ぱ、ぱ、パンツ？えっ？
Sorry, Miko-miko, but my "Pants" are coming up next. / Pa... Pa... Pants? What?
PANTS
Don't worry, don't flex
Don't worry, be naked
But wear at least pants
Animal, naked
Nature, naked
People, naked
But wear at least pants
Don't worry, don't flex
Don't worry, be naked
But wear at least pants
No pants, no fight
No pants, no style
No pants, no life
But wear at least pants
Kick your neck, kick your neck
Kick your neck, kick your neck, kick your neck
キン ネキ キン
King, naked, king
キンネキキン キンネキキン
King, naked, king, king, naked, king
キッキッネッキッキッキッネッキッキン ネキキン
King, naked, king, king, naked, king, king, naked, king
Don't worry, Don't flex
Don't worry, Be naked, Boundaries, pantsu!
Animal, naked
Nature, naked
People, naked
Boundaries, pantsu!
Don't worry, Don't flex, Don't worry, Don't flex
Don't worry, Be naked, Boundaries, pantsu!
You said naked, I said no. I said naked, you said no.
You are wearing, I say pantsu! I say wearing, you say pantsu!
キン ネキ キン ネキ キン
King, naked, king, naked, king
キッキッネッキッキッキッネッキッキン ネキキン
King, naked, king, king, naked, king
Hey!
Simon, push! Simon, push!
I'm wearing pantsu, but I can pose naked!
マフィオーザ
[Song: Mafiosa]
Ah, listen up
キラっと光る犬歯がお似合いの口が物語る
The mouth that suits the glittering canine teeth tells the story
リリカルがもくもくと充満し成すスモーキーなストーリー
Lyricals puff and fill, forming a smoky story
Let me see
不確かな平穏と確かな不安を纏い彷徨う
Wandering, clad in uncertain peace and certain anxiety
お仲間じゃないことに恐れ慄く
Fearing and trembling that we are not companions
十色の価値観 騒ぐラジカル 何がはじまる？
Ten-colored values, noisy radicals, what is beginning?
不器用な生き様に心痛む (Ahh)
Heart aches for a clumsy way of life (Ahh)
I wonder why 理性を欠いたサバイブ
I wonder why, a survival lacking reason
願っても願ってもなくならない
No matter how much I wish, it doesn't disappear
I wonder why 危険度ハイなマイライフ
I wonder why, my life with a high danger level
Do it again, Do it again
Chase chase, Where is my utopia こじ開ける扉
Chase, chase, where is my utopia? Prying open the door
Viva 現状打破なら飛び乗りな
Viva, if it's about breaking the status quo, hop on
くしゃくしゃの紙屑に傷ついたハート重ねる
Overlaying a wounded heart onto crumpled paper scraps
しわついたまま時を刻む（踊れ）
Ticking away time while wrinkled (Dance!)
数多のお目目から逃げた Back in the day
Fled from countless eyes, back in the day
ひた隠しているファンキーなヘッド
The funky head I've been hiding
個性の延長線上にあるギフトも誰かにとってはバグみたい
Even a gift on the extension of individuality seems like a bug to someone
伏し目を逸らし 行く当てもない
Looking down, turning away, with nowhere to go
現状 感情 洗浄 出来ず立ち往生
Unable to cleanse current emotions, at a standstill
抱いても泣いても足掻いても Fall...
Even if I embrace, cry, or struggle, I fall...
Uhhh 放浪 噛み締め 揺蕩う
Uhhh, wandering, biting down, swaying
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一歩前に踏み出す アニマル
Take a step forward, animal
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一丁前に 超前に 超前に (Straight out)
Quite decently, super forward, super forward (Straight out)
WIP aww WIP aww WIP aww aww aww
Critical Critical Criti Criti
Don't panic, Go too far far far
暗闇が Take over さながら予定調和
Darkness takes over, just like a pre-established harmony
覚えたての絶望にほだされ見る見る間に裏目を出す
Influenced by a newly learned despair, in no time it backfires
手招く反逆のアイコン 一抹の不安抱くも邂逅
The beckoning icon of rebellion, meeting despite holding a tinge of anxiety
平和ボケした連中を尻目に日陰繰り歩けば Dope Dope Dope
Walking through the shade while ignoring those who are peaceful and naive, dope dope dope
What a uhmmm...
山積みトラブルに追い追われ多忙
Chased and pursued by a mountain of trouble, so busy
やさぐれ罵倒にはなむけ発砲 (BANG!)
Firing a parting shot at moody abuse (BANG!)
Bang ba bang ba bang ba
ぶち抜く不条理 ヘッドばん
Blasting through absurdity, headbang!
出る杭打つのに必死なプライド
Pride desperate to hammer down the nail that sticks out
塗れのエネミーに見舞う超ヤバイもん
Inflicting something super dangerous on tainted enemies
狂った情緒で冷え切った体温 滾るこのエナジーは文字通りザイオン
Body temperature cooled down by crazy emotions, this boiling energy is literally Zion
運命捻じ曲げるトリガー 着火する煙たい Dogs のお通りだ (Goooo!)
The trigger that bends fate, make way for the smoky, igniting Dogs (Goooo!)
皆誰もがスペシャルな存在ってこと忘れた結果
The result of everyone forgetting that they are special beings
自分と違う箇所否定して突っぱねる それこそ欠陥
Denying and rejecting the parts that differ from oneself, that itself is a defect
たくさんの矛盾と向き合い続けて尚
Continuing to face many contradictions, yet...
一向になくならない愚かなる (Battle)
The foolishness never disappears (Battle)
悲愴 失踪 闘争 Never never end
Grief, disappearance, struggle, never never end
散らばる Hollow
Scattering Hollow
ぎらり剥き出しの牙と思惑が絡み合う
The glittering bared fangs and intentions entwine
消灯 深い夜と歌う
Lights out, singing with the deep night
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一歩前に踏み出す アニマル
Take a step forward, animal
Hey don't panic, Go too far far far
一丁前に 超前に 超前に (Straight out)
Quite decently, super forward, super forward (Straight out)
WIP aww WIP aww WIP aww aww aww
Critical Critical Criti Criti
Don't panic, Go too far far far
Work like a dog 只管に磨いたジョブ
Work like a dog, a job polished intently
ぼんやり未来が望遠鏡に浮かんだ今日
A blurry future floated in the telescope today
いつかのオメルタもスーベニア
The omerta from someday is also a souvenir
凍り付いた心を溶かす My whereabouts
Melting my frozen heart, my whereabouts
マフィオーザ 祝砲を放つ (Yeah)
Mafiosa fires a celebratory shot (Yeah)
アイネ・クライネ・ナハトムジーク 気怠い顔はグッバイ
Eine kleine Nachtmusik, goodbye to the listless face
マフィオーザ 祝福の歌 (Yeah)
Mafiosa, song of blessing (Yeah)
ようやく見つけた かけがえのない居場所
Finally found an irreplaceable place to belong
Say hoo! ほら一緒に踊ろう
Say hoo! Come on, let's dance together
Say hoo! また一緒に踊ろう
Say hoo! Let's dance together again
Say hoo! ずっと一緒に踊ろう
Say hoo! Let's dance together forever
ようやく気付いた ふたつとない居場所
Finally realized there's no other place to belong
いばしょー！
My place!
うわー！みんなー！
Wow! Everyone!
マフィオーサ、ライブ初お披露目、どうだった？
How was the first live reveal of "Mafiosa"?
ちょっと、「パンツ」と「マフィオーサ」で2曲続けてだったんですけど、
I performed "Pantsu" and "Mafiosa" back-to-back,
この「パンツ」っていう曲、めちゃめちゃ好きで、
but I really love this song called "Pantsu,"
あの、ずっと暇な時、めちゃめちゃ聴いてたので、
and I used to listen to it all the time whenever I was free.
今回歌えて嬉しいのと、
So I was happy to be able to sing it this time,
ころねすきーにね、ピンクのパンツを穿いて踊ってもらえたのが、
and seeing the Koronesuki wearing pink pants and dancing with me
凄く楽しかったので、
was so much fun!
みんな踊ってくれてありがとう！
Thank you all for dancing!
はい、でね、今回、マフィオーサのライブ初お披露目をしたくて、
Yes, and this time, I really wanted to do the live reveal of "Mafiosa,"
全部ね、ラップ曲でまとめてみたんですけど、どうだったかな？
so I put together a set of entirely rap songs. How was it?
ちょっと初めての試みだったから、すごいね、あの、
Since it was my first time trying something like this,
準備段階から今日に至るまでめっちゃドキドキで、
I was so nervous from the preparation stage all the way up to today.
なんか、みんな楽しんでくれるかな、とか思ってたんだけど、
I was wondering if everyone would enjoy it,
だからね、みんなが楽しんで、ノリノリになってくれてたら嬉しいなと思います。
so I hope you all had fun and got hyped up.
でね、原曲知らないよっていう方がね、結構いると思うんですけど、
Also, I'm sure there are quite a few of you who might not know the original songs,
あ、結構はいないか。いると思うんですけど、
oh, maybe not that many. But if you don't,
もしね、そういう方はぜひ、めちゃめちゃカッコいいのでね、全部の曲、原曲ぜひ聴いてみてください。
they are all super cool, so please definitely check out the original songs!
あ、最後に歌ったマフィオーサもですね、めちゃめちゃ原曲カッコいいので、
Ah, "Mafiosa," which I sang at the end, has an incredibly cool original version too,
ぜひ、みんな聴いてね！
so please listen to it, everyone!
はい！ということで、今回もあります！
All right! So, we have them again this time!
周年グッズです！こちら！
Our anniversary merchandise! Here they are!
急に来る。
It comes out of nowhere.
はい。え、今回はですね、なんと！うすた京介先生に、描き下ろししていただきました！
Yes! This time, believe it or not, Kyosuke Usuta-sensei drew the illustrations for us!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
１つずつ見ていきましょうかね。
Let's take a look at them one by one.
え、最初はですね、YB-2、久しぶりに見ました。え、うちのブランド「YB-2」です。
First up is YB-2—it's been a while since I saw that name. Yes, it's my own brand "YB-2."
YB-2の、え、うすた先生バージョンの、パーカーです！
The Usuta-sensei version of the YB-2 hoodie!
え、裏面に、え、イラストが来る感じですね。で、胸元に「YB-2」って入ってて、
The illustration is on the back, and "YB-2" is printed on the chest,
腕にね、あの、ころねのモチーフの、骨が入っております。これ、めちゃめちゃカッコいいと思うのでね、
and on the sleeve, there's a bone, which is my motif. I think this looks super cool,
お楽しみに！
so look forward to it!
はい、続いてこちら！
Next up is this!
こちらはですね、あの、パーカーと同じイラストのサコッシュです。
This is a sacoche with the same illustration as the hoodie.
なんか結構ね、イベントとか、フェスとか、なんか、みんなのね、イベントとかに来る時に、サコッシュ使ってる人結構いたなと思って、
I noticed that quite a few people wear sacoches when they come to our events or festivals,
ころねもサコッシュ出したい！ということで、サコッシュも出しました！
so I wanted to make one too! And so, we made a sacoche!
みんなぜひ使ってください！
Please make sure to use it!
続いてこちら！
Next is this!
こちらはですね、えーっと、ごめんなさいね。
This one is, let's see... I'm sorry.
え、ラップドッグキャップ！こちらはですね、
The Rap Dog Cap! This one is...
え、ひこさん先生のデザインで、あの、出させていただきました。ありがとうございます！
...designed by Hiko-san-sensei. Thank you so much!
え、ここにね、ころねの骨がクロスしてて、
The bones of my motif are crossed here on the front,
横に、またこれ、「YB-2」です。これも「YB-2」なのでね、
and on the side, it says "YB-2" again. Since this is also YB-2,
パーカーとサコッシュと帽子、え、全部「YB-2」のブランドでございます！
the hoodie, sacoche, and cap are all under the "YB-2" brand!
よろしくお願いします！
Please check them out!
はい、次！
Okay, next!
これはYB-2じゃない、ころねのランダムラバーストラップ！
This one is NOT YB-2: Korone's Random Rubber Straps!
こちらはね、フカヒレママに、描き下ろしてもらいました！ママ、ありがとう！
These were illustrated by Fukahire-mama! Thank you, Mama!
こちらね、4種類ランダムで。
These come in 4 random designs.
で、今回ね、ラップの曲が多かったということで、あの、ラップをしてるね、ころねのイラストもありますので、
Since we had a lot of rap songs this time, there is an illustration of Korone rapping!
ぜひ皆さん全種類目指して、よかったら、買ってみてください。
So if you want, aim for the full set and buy them!
通常衣装と、え、YB-2のジャンプスーツと、ドッグ、え、グッドドッグ衣装と、え、ラッパー衣装ですね。
It features my default outfit, the YB-2 jumpsuit, the Good Dog outfit, and the rapper outfit.
よかったら、はい、こちらもご検討ください。
If you like, please consider getting them!
そして、フルセットの購入特典は、
And the full set purchase bonus is...
え、うすた先生描き下ろしのですね、ポストカード！
...a postcard illustrated by Usuta-sensei!
数量限定版もありますけれど、
There is also a limited quantity version,
めちゃめちゃ、あの、用意しておりますので、あの、急がないで、
but we have prepared plenty of them, so you don't need to rush.
大丈夫です。あの、マジで、結構用意したので、
It's okay. Seriously, we made quite a lot,
あの、ゆっくりご購入ください。
so please take your time with your purchase.
はい、で、通常バージョンはね、箔押しの、複製サイン入りとなっております。
Yes, and the regular version comes with a foil-stamped printed signature.
はい、ということで、今回のライブもみんな、たくさん見てくれてありがとうございました！
All right, so thank you so much everyone for watching today's live stream!
以上、レイジードッグナイトでした！みんな、ほんと、いつもありがとうね！
That's all for Lazy DOOG Night! Thank you all so much, as always!
また会おう！
Let's meet again!
またねー！
See ya!
Lazy DOOG Night!
INUGAMI KORONE 7th ANNIV. LIVE